JIWON CHOE

(+1)713-906-2530 ♦ jiwon_choe@brown.edu 115 Waterman St. Providence, RI 02912, United States https://jiwon-choe.github.io

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My Ph.D. research focuses on the hardware and software co-design of concurrent data structures and data-intensive algorithms with emerging memory technologies, such as near-data-processing, in-memory computing, and byte-addressable non-volatile memory. This is a challenging problem, for new data structures and algorithms must preserve the high concurrency and strong correctness guarantees of existing data structures and algorithms, but at the same time take full advantage of the interesting features and work around the limitations introduced by the new memory technologies.

EDUCATION

Brown University, Providence, RI, USA

08/2016 - present

Ph.D. Candidate in Computer Science

Sc.M. in Computer Science (05/2018)

Advisors: Professors Iris Bahar & Maurice Herlihy

Rice University, Houston, TX, USA

08/2009 - 05/2013

B.S.E.E. in Electrical Engineering, cum laude

B.A. in Computer Science, cum laude

PUBLICATIONS

Jiwon Choe, Amy Huang, Tali Moreshet, Maurice Herlihy, R. Iris Bahar.

Concurrent Data Structures with Near-Data-Processing: an Architecture-Aware Implementation. In 31st ACM Symposium on Parallelism in Algorithms and Architectures (SPAA 2019).

https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3323191

This empirical evaluation of NDP-based concurrent data structures provides insight into memory access patterns of data structures and identifies the minimal hardware support needed in order to increase throughput and reduce energy consumption.

Jiwon Choe, Tali Moreshet, R. Iris Bahar, Maurice Herlihy.

Attacking Memory-Hard scrypt with Near-Data-Processing (extended abstract). In *The International Symposium on Memory Systems* (MEMSYS 2019).

https://dl.acm.org/citation.cfm?id=3357570

Memory-hard cryptographic functions exploit the non-trivial memory access costs of DRAM to hinder brute-force security attacks. This preliminary investigation focuses on scrypt, a widely used memory-hard key-derivation function, to look into how compute-capable memory may impact the security of such memory-hard functions.

OPEN SOURCE TOOLS

Brown-SMCSim: gem5 full-system simulator for near-data-processing

https://github.com/jiwon-choe/Brown-SMCSim

A gem5 full-system simulator that includes the architecture support and full software stack for near-data-processing. Extended from Azarkhish *et al.*'s SMCSim project. Used for evaluation in SPAA '19 and MEMSYS '19 papers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer at Oracle, Santa Clara, CA

07/2013 - 12/2015

Single Server Management – Hardware Management Pack

Developed cross-platform, cross-OS software for monitoring and maintaining the status of various hardware components on Oracle servers.

HONORS & AWARDS

2019 Best Student Presentation Award

The International Symposium on Memory Systems (MEMSYS 2019)

2018 Cadence Women in Tech Scholarship

\$5,000 award for women with strong academic record and leadership/passion in technology

- 2013 Tau Beta Pi, School of Engineering, Rice University
- 2012 Eta Kappa Nu, ECE Department, Rice University

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

ENGN 1630: Digital Electronics Systems Design

Brown University

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Fall 2019

Responsibilities include teaching lectures when professor is away on travel, making problem sets & exams, grading.

ELEC 220: Fundamentals of Computer Engineering

Rice University Spring 2011

Lab Assistant

Helped organize and proceed labs on: digital logic circuits and assembly language.

ELEC 241: Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering I

Rice University

Course Assistant

Fall 2011

Held weekly help sessions for problem sets on: time and frequency domain signal analysis, analog and digital signal processing, and signal transmission.

ELEC 242: Fundamentals of Electrical Engineering II

Rice University

Course Assistant

Spring 2012

Held weekly help sessions for problem sets on: basic electronic devices, circuits, and electromechanical systems.

CONFERENCE & WORKSHOP PRESENTATIONS

10/2019 Hybrid Skiplists: Combining the Best of Near-Data-Processing and Lock-Free Algorithms

Student Research Competition (at MICRO-52)

Career Workshop for Women and Minorities in Computer Architecture (at MICRO-52)

10/2019 Attacking Memory-Hard scrypt with Near-Data-Processing

The International Symposium on Memory Systems (MEMSYS 2019)

Received the Best Student Presentation Award

06/2019 Concurrent Data Structures with Near-Data-Processing: an Architecture-Aware Implementation

31st ACM Symposium on Parallelism in Algorithms and Architectures (SPAA 2019)

01/2019 Hardware-Software Coordination for High-Performance Concurrent Data Structures with Near-Data-Processing

2019 Boston Area Architecture Workshop

01/2018 Managing Concurrent Data Structures with Processing-In-Memory 2018 Boston Area Architecture Workshop

$10/2017 \quad \textbf{Managing Concurrent Data Structures with Processing-In-Memory}$

Career Workshop for Women and Minorities in Computer Architecture (at MICRO-50)

SERVICES

2018-current	1st year PhD student mentoring for Brown CS Department
2019	Student Volunteer for ASPLOS 2019
2018	Vice President for Rhode Island Central Korean Church Young Adult Ministry
2017	Organizer for Brown CS New Graduate Student Orientation
2014-2015	Volunteer Writer for techNeedle (Korean online media for tech-related news)
2012-2013	Treasurer for Rice IEEE Student Chapter